[
  {
    "questionNumber": 1,
    "questionType": "MCQ",
    "Answer": "C",
    "Marks": 1,
    "coreTopic": "General Aptitude",
    "subTopic": "Vocabulary",
    "question": "Despite his initial hesitation, Rehman's _______ to contribute to the success of the project never wavered. Select the most appropriate option to complete the above sentence.",
    "optionA": "ambivalence",
    "optionB": "satisfaction",
    "optionC": "resolve",
    "optionD": "revolve",
    "year": 2025,
    "exam": "GATE",
    "subject": "CS",
    "shift": 1
  },
  {
    "questionNumber": 2,
    "questionType": "MCQ",
    "Answer": "A",
    "Marks": 1,
    "coreTopic": "Engineering Mathematics",
    "subTopic": "Linear Algebra",
    "question": "If $A=\\begin{pmatrix}1&2\\\\ 2&-1\\end{pmatrix}$ then which ONE of the following is $A^{8}$?",
    "optionA": "$\\begin{pmatrix}25&0\\\\ 0&25\\end{pmatrix}$",
    "optionB": "$\\begin{pmatrix}125&0\\\\ 0&125\\end{pmatrix}$",
    "optionC": "$\\begin{pmatrix}625&0\\\\ 0&625\\end{pmatrix}$",
    "optionD": "$\\begin{pmatrix}3125&0\\\\ 0&3125\\end{pmatrix}$",
    "year": 2025,
    "exam": "GATE",
    "subject": "CS",
    "shift": 1
  },
  {
    "questionNumber": 3,
    "questionType": "MCQ",
    "Answer": "C",
    "Marks": 1,
    "coreTopic": "Engineering Mathematics",
    "subTopic": "Calculus",
    "question": "The value of x such that $x > 1$ satisfying the equation $\\int_{1}^{x}t \\ln t~dt = \\frac{1}{4}$ is",
    "optionA": "$\\sqrt{e}$",
    "optionB": "$e^{2}$",
    "optionC": "e",
    "optionD": "$e-1$",
    "year": 2025,
    "exam": "GATE",
    "subject": "CS",
    "shift": 1
  },
  {
    "questionNumber": 4,
    "questionType": "MCQ",
    "Answer": "B",
    "Marks": 1,
    "coreTopic": "Computer Networks",
    "subTopic": "Protocols",
    "question": "Consider the following statements: (i) Address Resolution Protocol (ARP) provides a mapping from an IP address to the corresponding hardware (link-layer) address. (ii) A single TCP segment from a sender S to a receiver R cannot carry both data from S to R and acknowledgement for a segment from R to S. Which ONE of the following is CORRECT?",
    "optionA": "Both (i) and (ii) are TRUE",
    "optionB": "(i) is TRUE and (ii) is FALSE",
    "optionC": "(i) is FALSE and (ii) is TRUE",
    "optionD": "Both (i) and (ii) are FALSE",
    "year": 2025,
    "exam": "GATE",
    "subject": "CS",
    "shift": 1
  },
  {
    "questionNumber": 5,
    "questionType": "NAT",
    "Answer": "21 to 21",
    "Marks": 1,
    "coreTopic": "Operating System",
    "subTopic": "Processes",
    "question": "Suppose in a multiprogramming environment, the following C program segment is executed. A process goes into I/O queue whenever an I/O related operation is performed. Assume that there will always be a context switch whenever a process requests for an I/O, and also whenever the process returns from an I/O. The number of times the process will enter the ready queue during its lifetime (not counting the time the process enters the ready queue when it is run initially) is (Answer in integer) ```c int main() { int x=0, i=0; scanf(\"%d\",&x); for( i=0; i<20; i++) { x=x+20; printf(\"%d\\n\",x); return 0; } } ```",
    "optionA": "NA",
    "optionB": "NA",
    "optionC": "NA",
    "optionD": "NA",
    "year": 2025,
    "exam": "GATE",
    "subject": "CS",
    "shift": 1
  },
  {
    "questionNumber": 6,
    "questionType": "MCQ",
    "Answer": "A",
    "Marks": 2,
    "coreTopic": "Algorithms",
    "subTopic": "MST",
    "question": "Let G be an edge-weighted undirected graph with positive edge weights. Suppose a positive constant a is added to the weight of every edge. Which ONE of the following statements is TRUE about the minimum spanning trees (MSTs) and shortest paths (SPs) in G before and after the edge weight update?",
    "optionA": "Every MST remains an MST, and every SP remains an SP.",
    "optionB": "MSTs need not remain MSTs, and every SP remains an SP.",
    "optionC": "Every MST remains an MST, and SPs need not remain SPs.",
    "optionD": "MSTs need not remain MSTs, and SPs need not remain SPs.",
    "year": 2024,
    "exam": "GATE",
    "subject": "CS",
    "shift": 1
  },
  {
    "questionNumber": 7,
    "questionType": "MCQ",
    "Answer": "C",
    "Marks": 2,
    "coreTopic": "Digital Logic",
    "subTopic": "Boolean Algebra",
    "question": "Which of the following Boolean algebraic equation(s) is/are CORRECT?",
    "optionA": "$\\overline{A}BC+A\\overline{B}\\overline{C}+\\overline{A}\\overline{B}\\overline{C}+A\\overline{B}C+ABC=BC+\\overline{B}\\overline{C}+\\overline{A}\\overline{B}$",
    "optionB": "$AB+\\overline{A}C+BC=AB+\\overline{A}C$",
    "optionC": "$(A+C)(\\overline{A}+B)=AB+\\overline{A}C$",
    "optionD": "$\\overline{(A+\\overline{B}+\\overline{D})(C+D)(\\overline{A}+C+D)(A+B+\\overline{D})}=\\overline{A}D+\\overline{C}\\overline{D}$",
    "year": 2024,
    "exam": "GATE",
    "subject": "CS",
    "shift": 1
  },
  {
    "questionNumber": 8,
    "questionType": "MCQ",
    "Answer": "D",
    "Marks": 2,
    "coreTopic": "General Aptitude",
    "subTopic": "Data Interpretation",
    "question": "Which one of the following options is correct for the given data in the table? | Iteration (i) | Input (I) | Output (X) | Output (Y) | |---------------|-----------|------------|----------------| | 0 | 20 | 20 | 20 | | 1 | -4 | 16 | -80 | | 2 | 10 | 26 | -800 | | 3 | 15 | 41 | -12000 |",
    "optionA": "$X(i)=X(i-1)+I(i)$; $Y(i)=Y(i-1)I(i)$; $i>0$",
    "optionB": "$X(i)=X(i-1)I(i);$ $Y(i)=Y(i-1)+I(i);$ $i>0$",
    "optionC": "$X(i)=X(i-1)I(i)$ $Y(i)=Y(i-1)I(i);$ $i>0$",
    "optionD": "$X(i)=X(i-1)+I(i);$ $Y(i)=Y(i-1)I(i-1)$; $i>0$",
    "year": 2024,
    "exam": "GATE",
    "subject": "CS",
    "shift": 1
  },
  {
    "questionNumber": 9,
    "questionType": "MCQ",
    "Answer": "D",
    "Marks": 2,
    "coreTopic": "General Aptitude",
    "subTopic": "Geometry",
    "question": "In the given figure, PQRS is a square of side 2 cm and PLMN is a rectangle. The corner L of the rectangle is on the side QR. Side MN of the rectangle passes through the corner S of the square. What is the area (in $cm^{2}$) of the rectangle PLMN? Note: The figure shown is representative.",
    "optionA": "$2\\sqrt{2}$",
    "optionB": "2",
    "optionC": "8",
    "optionD": "4",
    "year": 2024,
    "exam": "GATE",
    "subject": "CS",
    "shift": 1
  },
  {
    "questionNumber": 10,
    "questionType": "MCQ",
    "Answer": "D",
    "Marks": 2,
    "coreTopic": "General Aptitude",
    "subTopic": "Connectivity/Graph Theory",
    "question": "The diagram below shows a river system consisting of 7 segments, marked P, Q, R, S, T, U, and V. It splits the land into 5 zones, marked Z1, Z2, Z3, Z4, and Z5. We need to connect these zones using the least number of bridges. Out of the following options, which one is correct? Note: The figure shown is representative.",
    "optionA": "Bridges on P, Q, and T",
    "optionB": "Bridges on P, Q, S, and T",
    "optionC": "Bridges on Q, R, T, and V",
    "optionD": "Bridges on P, Q, S, U, and V",
    "year": 2024,
    "exam": "GATE",
    "subject": "CS",
    "shift": 1
  },
  {
    "questionNumber": 11,
    "questionType": "MCQ",
    "Answer": "C",
    "Marks": 1,
    "coreTopic": "Engineering Mathematics",
    "subTopic": "Linear Algebra",
    "question": "If $A=\\begin{pmatrix}1&2\\\\ 2&-1\\end{pmatrix}$ then which ONE of the following is $A^{8}$?",
    "optionA": "$\\begin{pmatrix}25&0\\\\ 0&25\\end{pmatrix}$",
    "optionB": "$\\begin{pmatrix}125&0\\\\ 0&125\\end{pmatrix}$",
    "optionC": "$\\begin{pmatrix}625&0\\\\ 0&625\\end{pmatrix}$",
    "optionD": "$\\begin{pmatrix}3125&0\\\\ 0&3125\\end{pmatrix}$",
    "year": 2024,
    "exam": "GATE",
    "subject": "CS",
    "shift": 1
  },
  {
    "questionNumber": 12,
    "questionType": "MCQ",
    "Answer": "C",
    "Marks": 1,
    "coreTopic": "Engineering Mathematics",
    "subTopic": "Calculus",
    "question": "The value of x such that $x > 1$ satisfying the equation $\\int_{1}^{x}t \\ln t~dt = \\frac{1}{4}$ is",
    "optionA": "$\\sqrt{e}$",
    "optionB": "$e^{2}$",
    "optionC": "e",
    "optionD": "$e-1$",
    "year": 2024,
    "exam": "GATE",
    "subject": "CS",
    "shift": 1
  }
]
